(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-25T22:30:15.097193",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
星炎 Fierstra Diva 虎金妃笑虎 3D Live 2026
Seien - Fierstra Diva - Koganehi Niko 3D Live 2026
幾千の 時を巡って今
Spanning across thousands of ages, now...
僕ら出会えたの
we have finally found each other.
ほら 見失わない
Look, I won't lose sight of you...
...ように
...so that...
手を離さないで
...you won't let go of my hand.
星降る海
[Ocean of Falling Stars]
ねぇ 耳を澄ませて
Hey, listen closely...
星の降る音聞こえるでしょう
You can hear the sound of falling stars, right?
もっと近くに来て
Come a little closer.
誰も知らない世界が待ってるの
A world nobody knows is waiting for us.
手をとって踊りましょう
Take my hand and let's dance.
始まりの合図鳴らせば
When the signal to begin sounds,
歌を 響け
Sing! Resound!
暗闇の道も続き 明かりが照らすの
Even along dark paths, light will shine through.
空 海の向こう 君のもとまで
Across the sky and sea, all the way to you,
響くように歌えるかな
I wonder if I can sing so that it reaches you.
どんなときも ここに立ってるよ
No matter when, I'll be standing right here,
祈っているからさ
Because I'm praying for you.
ほら キラキラ輝く星は
Look, the sparkling, shining stars...
色褪せず太古から
Never fading since ancient times,
照らし続けてる 君と辿り着けるさ
Keep shining on us. Together, we can reach it.
心には逢いたい
In my heart, there's someone I want to see.
誰かが居て 羅針盤みたいね
They act just like my compass.
そっと目を開けてみて
Gently open your eyes...
見えるものだけが リアルじゃないの
Reality isn't only what you can see with your eyes.
君と居る世界は 童話の記憶に眠るのさ
The world I inhabit with you lies asleep in memories of fairy tales.
歌を 響け
Sing! Resound!
潮の満ち引きが満ちていくの
The ebb and flow of the tide swells up.
途切れかけた 夢を見ても大丈夫 一人にはしないよ
Even if your dream nearly breaks apart, it's okay. I won't leave you alone.
何度だって 互いの引力で 引き寄せ合うんだよ
Time and time again, through our mutual gravity, we draw each other close.
空 海の匂い 君に届いたかな
Across the sky, did the scent of the sea reach you?
距離なんてないのかな
I wonder if distance even exists between us.
こんなときも きっとどこかで 見守っているからさ
Even at times like this, surely somewhere, I'm watching over you.
ほら くしゃくしゃになって笑う
Look, bursting into laughter...
日々を集めて紡いだ未来
A future spun from gathering those days.
一歩踏み出す先も 君と
Even the step forward lies together with you,
心震わせて
Making our hearts tremble.
重なる幸いは
Overlapping fortunes...
物語を巡るわ
...traverse through our story.
ニコたんが来たー！
Nikotan is here!
hololive DEV_IS FLOWGLOWのお笑い担当、虎金妃ニコです！
I'm Koganei Niko, in charge of comedy for hololive DEV_IS FLOWGLOW!
ニコたんだよー！誕生日だー！ガオー！
It's Nikotan~! It's my birthday~! Rawr~!
ニコたん初の生誕ライブ「聖炎 -FIRESTRA DIVA-」にご来場いただき
Thank you all so much for coming to Nikotan's first birthday live, "Sacred Flame -FIRESTRA DIVA-"!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
本日のハッシュタグは #ニコたん生たん2026
Today's hashtag is #NikotanSeitan2026!
たん はニコたんの「たん」なので平仮名です！
The "tan" is the same "tan" as in Nikotan, so it's spelled in hiragana!
こちらでね、スクショたくさん撮って感想どしどしポストしてください！
Take lots of screenshots with that and post your impressions!
頼んます！
Please, I'm counting on you!
今回のタイトル「聖炎 -FIRESTRA DIVA-」、こちらは
The title of this concert, "Sacred Flame -FIRESTRA DIVA-",
FIRESTRA、「炎」「星」「虎」の3つの要素を掛け合わせたトリプルミーニング！
has a triple meaning combining "Flame" (FIRE), "Star" (ASTRA), and "Tiger" (TORA)!
ニコたんが作っちゃいました！
Nikotan came up with it herself!
まあニコたんが星で、みんなから炎もらってて〜みたいな！
Like, Nikotan is the star, and I'm receiving flames from everyone~!
フェスでさ、初めてのフェスでみんなのペンライト赤かったでしょ？
Remember at the festival—my first festival—everyone's penlights were red, right?
あれはね、炎だったの！このライブの匂わせをしていたわけです！
That was actually flame! I was dropping hints for this live concert all along!
計画通りってわけよ！
It was all according to plan!
D私と そんなニコたんの炎を感じられるような感じで
This live performance is centered on singing lots of songs where you can feel the spark between D-watashi and Nicotan...
たくさん歌っていく歌唱がメインのライブになっております
...where you can feel our passion as we sing our hearts out!
1曲目は『星振る海』を歌わせていただきました
For the first song, we performed "Hoshi Furu Umi."
皆さん どうでしたでしょうか？ニコたん 清楚でしたでしょうか？
How was it, everyone? Was Nicotan refined and graceful?
この後はゲストのD私との時間です
Up next is our time with guest D-watashi!
それではゲストパート レッツゴー！
And now, for the guest section, let's go!
涙が 夜に溶けて 空が今日も遠くなる
My tears melt into the night, and the sky grows distant again today.
未来が 閉じたように 暗闇が満ちている
As if the future has closed up, darkness fills the air.
醜い心も 掠れそうな言葉も
My ugly heart, and my fading words too...
すべて透かしたように 星が輝いていた
As if seeing through it all, the stars were shining.
夜鷹のように高く 空を駆けていけたら
If only I could fly high through the sky like a nightjar,
綺麗だって囃されて 特別になれたのに
I would have been praised as beautiful and become special.
そう 俯いた目には 憧れしか映らない
Yes, my downcast eyes reflect nothing but yearning.
誰かの書いた地図じゃ 灯る場所は探せない
I can't find my place to shine using a map drawn by someone else.
僕らの現実は 情けなくふっと息して
Our reality pathetically sighs,
気を抜けば明日が 昨日になってしまう
and if we let our guard down, tomorrow will turn into yesterday.
これはそう 今日を諦めなかった故のストーリー
This is, yes, the story of not giving up on today.
風切り羽で響かせて 空を目指して
Letting our flight feathers resonate, aiming for the sky.
惨めになって嫌になったって 輝いてる夢を叶え
Even if I feel miserable and hate it all, I'll fulfill my shining dream.
羽はとっくの昔に生えていた
The wings had sprouted a long time ago.
吐き出す息が白さ増して 声も聞こえなくなって
My exhaled breath turns white, and my voice can no longer be heard.
燃え上がる体温が夜空を焦がすまで
Until my burning body heat scorches the night sky.
誰よりもっともっと越えて 羽ばたいた星の一瞬を
Going far, far beyond anyone else, that instant of a soaring star...
夜空はずっと待っている 灯る日を待っている
The night sky has always been waiting, waiting for the day to ignite.
きっと きっと
Surely, surely...
いつか、なんて誤魔化して 誰かに擦り付けて
Deceiving myself with "someday", shifting the blame onto someone else...
どこか、なんて慰めて 何かにすがっている
Comforting myself with "somewhere", clinging to something...
それこそが僕だ 汚れ切った心だ
That's exactly who I am, a completely tainted heart.
夜鷹にはなれないな だから今日飛んだんだ
I can't become a nightjar, that's why I flew today.
僕らの結末は 面白いくらい弱気で
Our ending is absurdly faint-hearted,
予測なんて一つも 当てにならないから
because not a single prediction can be relied upon.
これはまだ 僕を諦めなかった故のストーリー
This is still the story of not giving up on myself.
枯れた喉を響かせて 後悔を追い越して
Letting my dry throat resonate, overtaking regret.
世界にとって僕にとって ふさわしかった役なんて
A role that was suitable for the world or for me...
いらない 知らない 所詮僕ら僕らだ
I don't need it, I don't care, after all we are who we are.
それならどうかこの涙を 忘れないで
In that case, please, don't forget these tears.
疲れ果ててこの空から 落ちるまで
Until I'm completely exhausted and fall from this sky.
今よりもっともっと越えて 羽ばたいた星が泣いている
Going far, far beyond now, the soaring star is crying...
夜空が白け出している 日が登り出している
The night sky is turning white, the sun is starting to rise.
そっと
Gently...
あれから始まって これから終わっていく
Starting from back then, ending from now on.
一つ一つ一瞬を 確かめていく
Confirming each and every moment.
誰かも同じじゃない 誰にも似ていない
No one is the same, no one is alike.
一人一人とても不確かな 空を飛んでいるのさ
Each and every one of us is flying through a very uncertain sky.
僕らの現実は 気持ち一つでシャープして
Our reality sharpens with a single feeling,
怯えていた明日を 昨日にしてしまえる
and can turn the tomorrow we feared into yesterday.
これはそう 今日を諦めなかった故のストーリー
This is, yes, the story of not giving up on today.
風切り羽で響かせて 空を目指して
Letting our flight feathers resonate, aiming for the sky.
惨めになって嫌になったって 輝いてる夢を叶え
Even if I feel miserable and hate it all, I'll fulfill my shining dream.
羽はとっくの昔に生えていた
The wings had sprouted a long time ago.
吐き出す息が白さ増して 声も聞こえなくなって
My exhaled breath turns white, and my voice can no longer be heard.
燃え上がる体温が夜空を焦がすまで
Until my burning body heat scorches the night sky.
...澄み渡って
Clear and serene,
誰よりもっと遠くへ
farther than anyone else,
羽ばたいた星の
the instant of a star
一瞬が
taking flight...
青空を照らし出している
is illuminating the blue sky,
淡く光っている
gently shining,
ずっと
forever,
forever.
Magia
いつか君が瞳に灯す愛の光が
Someday, the light of love you kindle in your eyes
時を超えて
will transcend time,
滅び急ぐ世界の夢を
and surely destroy one dream
確かに一つ
of a world rushing to ruin...
壊すだろう
it will surely shatter.
躊躇いを飲み干して
Drinking down your hesitation,
君が望むものは何？
what is it that you desire?
こんな欲望深い憧れの
At the end of such a covetous longing,
行方に儚い
is there a fleeting tomorrow
明日はあるの？
waiting for us?
子供の頃夢に見てた
Like the ancient magic
古の魔法のように
I dreamed of as a child,
闇さえ砕く力で
with power that can shatter even the darkness,
微笑む君に会いたい
I want to meet you smiling.
怯えるこの手の中には
In these trembling hands
手折られた花の勇気
lies the courage of a plucked flower;
思いだけが頼る全て
my feelings are all I can rely on
光を
to awaken
呼び覚ます
the light...
願い
My wish.
いつか君も誰かの為に 強い力を
Someday, you too will seek a strong power
望むのだろう
for the sake of someone else.
愛が胸を捉えた夜に
On the night love grips your heart,
未知の言葉が
unknown words
生まれてくる
will come to life.
迷わずに行けるなら
If I can go without wavering,
心が砕けてもいいわ
I don't care if my heart breaks.
いつも目の前の哀しみに
I want a spell
立ち向かうための
to confront the sorrow
呪文が欲しい
that always stands before my eyes.
君はまだ夢見る記憶
You are a memory still dreaming,
私は眠らない明日
while I face a sleepless tomorrow.
二人が出会う奇跡を
To claim the miracle
勝ち取るために進むわ
of our meeting, I will push forward.
怯えるこの手の中には
In these trembling hands
手折られた花の刃
is the blade of a plucked flower;
思いだけが生きる全て
my feelings are all that keeps me alive
心に
as I brandish
振りかざす
my wish
願い
in my heart.
囚われた太陽の輝く
Back when I loved the book of Wonderland
不思議の国の本が好きだった頃
where a captive sun shone bright,
願いはきっと叶うと
I believed in the fairy tales
教えるお伽噺を
that taught me wishes
信じた
would surely come true.
いつか君が瞳に宿す愛の光が
Someday, the light of love that shines in your eyes...
静かに咲き乱れていた
Bloomed wildly in quiet,
古の魔法を優しく
the gentle magic of ancient times.
世界を変える力が
"The power to change the world
その手にあると囁く
lies within your hands," it whispers.
終わらない夢を見よう
Let us dream an endless dream,
君と行く時の中で
in this time I travel with you.
想いだけが生きる全て
My feelings alone are all I live for,
命を作るのは
and what creates my life...
願い
is my wish.
朝まで踊る夢だけ見せて
Show me only a dream of dancing until morning.
時計の鐘が解く魔法
The magic that the clock's chime undoes.
曖昧な指 誘う階段
Ambiguous fingers, inviting stairs,
三段飛ばしに跳ねていく
leaping three steps at a time.
馬車の中で震えてた
I was trembling inside the carriage,
惨めな古着
in miserable old clothes.
めくり廻る夜の舞踏
The night's ball turning round and round.
見知らぬ顔探す
Searching for an unfamiliar face,
囁くあの声が
that whispering voice...
握り締めた刃突き立て
Thrust the blade you tightly gripped,
すべてを奪えと
to snatch everything away.
みなしご集う城
In the castle where orphans gather,
笑み仮面に描いて
painting smiles on their masks.
偽りの慈しみさえ
Even false affection...
羽で包む熾天使
a seraph wraps in its wings.
灰の中で赤く溶けて混じる
Melting and mixing red in the ashes,
硝子の靴
the glass slipper.
今更帰る 震えているの
Returning now, are you trembling?
あなたが目をやる時計
The clock you glance at...
靴脱ぎ踊るスロープ抜けて
Slipping off shoes, escaping down the slope,
喉まで伸びる指の先で
with fingertips reaching to the throat.
掬う雫口付けして
Kissing the scooped-up drop,
走る衝動 背骨抜けていく
a rushing impulse runs down the spine,
切なさ
such heartbreak.
鐘は鳴らさないで
Don't let the bell toll,
あなたにひざまづき
kneeling down to you.
まだダメと叫んだ右手
The right hand that cried, "Not yet!"
突き刺すサヨナラ
thrusts a parting blow.
消せない硝煙を香水に纏う姫
A princess wearing indelible gunpowder smoke as perfume.
強い瞳 僕の凍った
Strong eyes pierce right through...
仮面ごと撃ち抜く
my frozen mask.
今も耳にあなたの吐息が
Even now, your breath pierces my ears...
突き刺さるの 遠い夢
like a distant dream.
ステンドグラスごし光る月が
The moon shining through stained glass...
君にかぶせたベール
casts a veil over you.
ドレス膝で裂いて
Tearing the dress at the knees,
ティアラは投げ捨てて
throwing away the tiara.
見つめ合う瞳と瞳が
Eyes gazing into eyes...
火花を放つ
send sparks flying.
孤独な魂が 炎をあげ 惹かれあう
Lonely souls ignite in flames, drawn to each other.
その涙すくえないなら
If I cannot save those tears,
まるで一人遊び
It's just like playing alone.
時よ止まれ 今は
Time, stand still, for now...
あなたに酔いしれて
I am intoxicated by you.
揺れる鼓動一つ一つを
Every single swaying heartbeat,
刻みつけてたい
I want to carve deep into my memory.
とどまれ 熱く濡れ
Stay, passionately drenched,
打ち付ける高まりに
amid this pounding surge of excitement,
これ以上は動けないよ
I can't move any further than this.
まるでペアに似てる
It's almost as if we're a pair.
そばにいても 離れたまま
Even side by side, we remain apart,
ひとつになれない連星 アルビレオ
a binary star, Albireo, that can never become one.
ああ 君が思うよりも 僕は君でいっぱいだ
Ah, more than you think, I am completely filled with you.
流星みたいな移ろいを
A fleeting shift like a shooting star,
片時も離さず見ていたいのか
I want to watch without taking my eyes off even for a moment.
ああ 僕が思うよりも 君はずっとずっと遠い
Ah, more than I think, you are so much further away.
重なったように見える仕草
Gestures that look as though they overlap...
苦しくなるほどに美しいな
are beautiful to the point of hurting.
君が好きって感情が 残らず夜空を飾っている
The feeling of liking you decorates the entire night sky.
心が余った言い訳を
An excuse born from an overflowing heart,
愛だなんて呼びたくない
I don't want to call something like love.
君は藍に浮かんだアルビレオ この心を奪ったまま
Floating in indigo, you are Albireo, having stolen my heart away.
いらないのなら返してよ
If you don't need it, give it back,
他に置き場もないけどさ
even though I have nowhere else to put it.
いまもアイミスユーの切れ端が
Even now, fragments of "I miss you"
成層圏で燃えて
burn up in the stratosphere.
そばにいても離れたまま
Even side by side, we remain apart,
ひとつになれない連星 アルビレオ
a binary star, Albireo, that can never become one.
何光年先で輝いてる 君に君に恋をしたんだ
I fell in love with you, shining light-years away.
何光年か測れぬほど 君の光が眩しすぎたから
Because your light was far too dazzling to measure how many light-years away it was...
から
Because...
君が好きって感情で それだけで星が回っている
Just with the feeling of liking you, the stars keep revolving.
明日を生きぬく言い訳を
An excuse to live through tomorrow,
愛だなんて呼んでみたい
I want to try calling it love.
君は藍に浮かんだアルビレオ この心を奪ったまま
Floating in indigo, you are Albireo, having stolen my heart away.
いらないのなら返してよ
If you don't need it, give it back,
他に置き場もないけどさ
even though I have nowhere else to put it.
いまもアイミスユーの切れ端が
Even now, fragments of "I miss you"
成層圏で燃えて
burn up in the stratosphere.
そばにいても離れたまま
Even side by side, we remain apart,
ひとつになれない連星
a binary star that can never become one.
君は愛の色さ アルビレオ この心焦がしたんだ
You are the color of love, Albireo, scorching my heart.
誰より近く恋してた
I was in love with you closer than anyone else,
届くわけもないのにさ
even though it could never reach you.
いまも温度を超えた高なりが
Even now, a pounding pulse exceeding temperature
君が好きと叫ぶ
shouts out that I love you.
離れていても消えないまま
Even separated, without fading away,
ふたつになれない二重星
a double star that can never split into two,
アルビレオ
Albireo.
子どもの頃 見上げた
When I was a child, I looked up at...
夜の空に
In the night sky,
想いを抱いた
I held my feelings.
あのひとつひとつに
In each and every one of them,
誰かの願いがこもってる
someone's wish is contained.
そのひとつが
If one of those
あなたで
is you,
すぐとなりで笑ってて
smiling right beside me...
ねぇ 時間を止めれるなら
Hey, if I could stop time,
この1秒を切り取って
I'd capture this single second.
星降る夜に
On a starry night,
ただあなたに会いたい
I just want to see you.
あなたの名前を 祈るようにそっと
Softly whispering your name as if praying,
何度も抱きしめているよ
I hold you close time and time again.
もう私も大人ね
I've grown up now too, haven't I?
変わったこと
Things that have changed,
変わらないこと
things that remain the same...
止まらない時計の針が
The unstoppable hands of the clock
冷たく胸を刻んだ
cold-heartedly carved into my heart.
でもあなたに出会って
But after meeting you,
日々の眩しさを教えて
you showed me the brilliance of each day.
まだ少し怖いけど
Though I'm still a little afraid,
今を生み出せる気がしてるよ
I feel like I can create a new present now.
星降る夜に
On a starry night,
会いたいが集まるばかり
my longing to see you only grows.
あなたの名前を 祈るようにそっと
Softly whispering your name as if praying,
何度も抱きしめているよ
I hold you close time and time again.
高鳴る鼓動が
My racing heartbeat
体を追い越していく
gets ahead of my own body.
私の名前を 特別にしてくれたの
You made my name something special.
今はただ抱きしめてたいの
Right now, I just want to hold you close.
いつも想ってるよ
I'm always thinking of you.
かじかんだ手に ぬくもり
Warmth for these numb hands...
目を閉じて
Close your eyes,
その先へ
and move beyond.
星降る夜に
On a starry night,
ただあなたに会いたい
I just want to see you.
あなたの名前を 祈るようにそっと
Softly whispering your name as if praying,
何度も抱きしめているよ
I hold you close time and time again.
高鳴る鼓動で
With my heart pounding fast,
裸足のまま駆けていく
I run barefoot.
私の名前を 特別にしてくれたの
You made my name something special.
あなたが照らし続けてる
You continue to shine your light.
星降る夜に
On a starry night...
Seid ihr das Essen? Nein, wir sind der Jäger!
Are you the prey? No, we are the hunter!
Feuerroter Pfeil und Bogen
Crimson bow and arrow
踏まれた花の 名前も知らずに
Without knowing the name of the trampled flower,
地に墜ちた鳥は 風を待ち侘びる
the fallen bird eagerly awaits the wind.
踏まれた
...trampled
花の名前も知らずに
Without even knowing the name of the flower,
地に堕ちた鳥は風を待ち侘びる
the fallen bird eagerly awaits the wind.
祈ったところで何も変わらない
Praying will change nothing.
今を変えるのは戦う覚悟だ
What changes the present is the resolve to fight...
屍踏み越えて
Stepping over corpses,
進む意思を嗤う豚よ
pigs that sneer at the will to press forward,
家畜の安寧 虚偽の繁栄 死せる餓狼の自由を!
enjoy livestock's peace, false prosperity, and freedom!
囚われた屈辱は
The humiliation of captivity
反撃の嚆矢だ
is the signal arrow for counterattack.
城壁の其の彼方
Beyond those city walls,
獲物を屠る Jäger!
slaying the prey—Jäger!
迸る殺意に 其の身を灼きながら
As your body burns with surging intent to kill,
黄昏に緋を穿つ
pierce the twilight with scarlet—
紅蓮の弓矢
the Crimson Bow and Arrow!
矢を番え追いかける 標的は逃がさない
Nocking an arrow and giving chase, never letting it escape.
矢を放ち追い詰める 決して逃がさない
Releasing the arrow and cornering it, never letting it escape.
限界まで引き絞る はじ切れそうな弦
Drawing the bowstring to its limit, almost snapping,
標的が息絶えるまで 何度でも放つ
loose again and again until the target stops breathing.
獲物を殺すのは 凶器でも技術でもない
What kills the prey is neither weapon nor skill,
研ぎ澄まされた お前自身の殺意だ
it is your own honed intent to kill.
Wir sind der Jäger 焔のように熱く!
Wir sind der Jäger, hot as flames!
Wir sind der Jäger 氷のように冷ややかに!
Wir sind der Jäger, cold as ice!
Wir sind der Jäger 己を矢に込めて!
Wir sind der Jäger, pouring ourselves into the arrow!
Wir sind der Jäger 全てを貫いて征け!
Wir sind der Jäger, pierce through everything!
Angriff auf die Titanen.
Attack on the Titans.
Der Junge von einst wird bald zum Schwert greifen.
The boy of back then will soon reach for the sword.
Wer nur seine Ohnmacht bedauert, kann nichts verändern.
Those who merely lament powerlessness change nothing.
Der Junge von einst wird bald das schwarze Schwert ergreifen.
The boy of back then will soon grasp the black sword.
Hass und Zorn sind eine zweischneidige Klinge.
Hatred and anger are a double-edged blade.
Bald, eines Tages, wird er dem Schicksal die Zähne zeigen.
Soon, one day, he will bare his teeth at fate.
何かを変えることができるのは
The ones who can change something
何かを捨てることができるもの
are those capable of casting something aside.
何一つリスク等背負わないままで
Without taking on any risk,
何かが叶う等...
expecting something to come true...
暗愚の想定 ただの幻影 今は無謀な勇気も
Foolish assumptions, mere illusions; reckless courage,
自由の先鋒 賭けの攻勢 走る奴隷に勝利を!
freedom's vanguard—victory to the running slaves!
架せられた不条理は 進撃の嚆矢だ
The absurdity imposed upon us is the signal arrow of attack.
奪われた其の地平 世界を望む《自由》
Beyond that stolen horizon lies freedom—Eren!
止まらない衝動に 其の身を侵されながら
As your body is consumed by unstoppable impulse,
宵闇に紫を運ぶ――冥府の弓矢
carry purple into dusk—the Bow and Arrow of the Underworld!
ということで！スペシャルゲスト、かわいいかわいいちまちゃんに来ていただきましたー！
And with that! Our special guest, the super cute Chima-chan, has joined us!
はーい！にじさんじ所属、上から読んでも下から読んでも町田ちまです！ニコちゃんお誕生日おめでとうー！
Hi! From Nijisanji, whether you read it forwards or backwards, I'm Machita Chima! Happy Birthday, Niko-chan!
ありがとう、ちまちゃん！
Thank you, Chima-chan!
気づいたらこんなことになってたね、ちまちゃん。
Before I knew it, things ended up like this, Chima-chan.
なんかね、大きくなっちゃってた。
Somehow, I grew really big.
大きくなっちゃってるっていうか... すごいサイズになってるんだけど...
Saying you "grew big" is an understatement... You're an incredible size...
後ろから光もさ...
And there's even light radiating from behind you...
そんなの後光が綺麗でしょう？
That halo in the back looks pretty, right?
綺麗だねー 似合うよ、ちまちゃん
It's pretty! It suits you, Chima-chan.
ありがとう
Thank you.
いや、今日はね、ちまちゃんと「火炎」を歌わせていただいたんだけど
Today, Chima-chan and I got to sing "Kaen,"
やっぱりちまちゃんのハイトーンも好きなんだけど
and while I love Chima-chan's high tones,
かっこよさも好きなのよ
I also love how cool you can sound!
おー、ありがとう
Oh, thank you.
なんかそんなふたつを混ぜられたらいいなと思って今回選びました
I chose this song hoping we could blend those two together.
ありがとう 一緒に歌えて嬉しかったー
Thank you! I was so happy to sing together!
えー！良かったー！
Yay, I'm so glad!
にこたんとバトルできて楽しかったー
Battling with Nico-tan was so much fun!
もう大変だったよ、もう！
It was so intense, seriously!
パカパカパカから嬉しいです
I'm so happy!
え、あのゴーレムは何だったの？
Wait, what was that golem back there?
うん、あれは町田の眷属のゴーレムです
Mm, that was the golem of Machita's kin.
そうだよね！言わせたみたいになってるけど…
Right! It feels like I forced you to say that, but...
いやもう、すごい強かったよ、町田ちゃんのゴーレムが！
Man, Machita-chan's golem was super strong!
ねー、めちゃくちゃ強かったけど、倒されちゃったんだよね、にこちゃんに
Yeah, it was super strong, but Nico-chan defeated it!
そうだよね、にこたん強かったからね
That's right, Nico-tan was really strong!
にこちゃんのおかげでなんか町田自身もパワーが…
Thanks to Nico-chan, Machita herself lost her power...
あ、そがれて…
Ah, drained...
ちまちゃん！あーもうダメかも知れない！
Chima-chan! Ah, I might not make it!
時間が、ない！
There's no time!
にこちゃん本当におめでとう！ありがとう！これからもよろしくね！またね！バイバイ！
Nico-chan, happy birthday! Thank you so much! Looking forward to working together! See ya! Bye-bye!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
Party is over
それでも踊りたかった
Still, I wanted to dance
眠れないくらい
So restless I can't sleep,
情熱の火はいつしか いつつの日にか
the flame of passion will, before I know it, someday...
端から気づいている 炎はいつか消える
I've known from the start that the flame will eventually go out
ねえ 何も要らないはずだった
Hey, I wasn't supposed to need anything
なのにまだ I'm so serious
Yet I'm still so serious
ああ まだ間に合う
Ah, there's still time
ああ ただ burn it up baby
Ah, just burn it up baby
Sorry darling そんなに甘くないよ
Sorry darling, it's not that sweet
でもきっとそんなに悪くないよ
But surely it's not that bad
ああ Give me fire
Ah, give me fire
Light it up baby 燃やしちゃうぜ yeah
Light it up baby, we'll burn it up, yeah
Yeah...
燃えろよ 燃えろよ 炎よ燃えろ
Burn, burn, burn, oh flame
千代も八千代も変わりもせずに 人のなりいとをかし 全部燃やせ八百屋お七
Unchanging through thousands of years, human nature is so curious, burn it all, Yaoya Oshichi!
出でよ 舞えよ 火の粉 焚き付けるのが仕事
Come forth, dance, sparks! Kindling the fire is my job
ガソリンとステロイド 燃えるさまはお見事
Gasoline and steroids, what a splendid sight as it burns
火遊びはしない ぬるいまね出来ない
I don't play with fire, no half-hearted moves here
しけたカルマ トラウマ 燃やし尽くす マグマ ドラマ
Stale karma and trauma, burning it out, magma drama
この飽くなき渇き 青い炎みたい
This insatiable thirst, like a blue flame
死は過去のひとつ隣 やがて全てひとつとなり
Death is just next to the past, soon everything becomes one
Love is dying
でもまだ消えてないから
But since it hasn't gone out yet
忘れてみたい
I want to try forgetting it
情熱の火はいつしか いつつの日にか
The flame of passion will, before I know it, someday...
身体は気づいている 僕らはいつか消える
My body realizes that one day we will disappear
緩やかに若さを溶かして
Slowly melting youth away
泣かないで Why so serious?
Don't cry, why so serious?
ああ まだ間に合う
Ah, there's still time
ああ ただ burn it up baby
Ah, just burn it up baby
Sorry darling そんなに甘くないよ
Sorry darling, it's not that sweet
でもきっとそんなに悪くないよ
But surely it's not that bad
ああ Give me fire
Ah, give me fire
Light it up baby 燃やしちゃうぜ yeah
Light it up baby, we'll burn it up, yeah
Yeah...
足りない 足りない 足りない 注ぐ火に油！
Not enough, not enough, not enough! Adding fuel to the fire!
Sorry darling hurry up
ああ まだ間に合う
Ah, there's still time
Sorry darling hurry up
ああ ただ burn it up
Ah, just burn it up
Give me fire
Light it up baby 燃やしちゃうぜ yeah
Light it up baby, we'll burn it up, yeah
Party is over
それでも踊りたかった
Still, I wanted to dance
魂の色は何色ですか
What color is the color of your soul?
「もういっそ 折れたままで」
"I might as well stay broken..."
捨てるほど 逃げ出すほど
Enough to discard, enough to run away...
強くないよ ほら
I'm not that strong, see?
もう一度 鼓動高鳴る
Once again, my heart beats fast.
何が正しいかなんて
What is right or wrong,
わからないけど
I don't know, but...
形のないものばかりが
Only shapeless things
大切になって行く
keep becoming important to me.
飾らない言葉だけが
Only unadorned words
強く結ばれてる
are strongly tied together.
また躓いて 転がって
Tripping and tumbling again,
それでも砕けない
even so, I remain unbroken.
魂の色は何色ですか
What color is the color of your soul?
ただ傷ついて 強がって
Just getting hurt and putting up a front,
それでも見つけたいよ
yet I still want to find it.
魂のカタチ
The shape of the soul,
確かめてるよ
I'm confirming it now.
深い地の底で一人
Deep beneath the earth, alone,
扉と鍵を探す
searching for a door and a key.
おとぎ話は ほら
Fairy tales, you see,
泡の様に全部消えて
disappear entirely like bubbles.
葛藤 残像だけ
Conflicts and afterimages alone...
次の頁へ
To the next page.
伸びてく枝葉が分かれて
The growing branches split,
それぞれの道を行く
heading down their separate paths.
寂しい思い出だけが
Only lonely memories
強く根を張ってる
take deep root.
また貫いて 失って
Piercing through and losing again,
それでも挫けない
yet I still won't give up.
心はどこに 器はどこに
Where is my heart? Where is my vessel?
ただ残されて 抜け落ちて
Just left behind, slipping away,
それでも伝えたいよ
yet I still want to convey it.
魂の日々を
The days of the soul,
魂の意志を
the will of the soul,
ずっと
forever...
魂の色は
The color of the soul...
何色ですか
What color is it?
赤い色ですか
Is it red?
青い色ですか
Is it blue?
魂の色は
The color of the soul...
何色ですか
What color is it?
透明な過去に
In a transparent past,
不透明な明日に
in an opaque tomorrow,
生きるあなたは 何色ですか
living as you do, what color are you?
また躓いて 転がって
Tripping and tumbling again,
それでも砕けない
even so, I remain unbroken.
魂の色は何色ですか
What color is the color of your soul?
ただ傷ついて 強がって
Just getting hurt and putting up a front,
それでも見つけたいよ
yet I still want to find it.
魂のカタチ
The shape of the soul,
確かめてるよ
I'm confirming it now.
ずっと
Forever...
その胸にしまった火に憧れた
I longed for the fire you kept in your heart.
飲み込まれて消されてしまいそうで
Feeling as if I'd be swallowed and erased,
夕焼けみたいに温かくて
warm like a sunset,
寂しくて強かったその火に
lonely and strong, to that fire...
選んだあげく間違えた
After choosing, I made a mistake,
よく晴れた日を未だに思い出す
I still remember that clear, sunny day.
目を伏せたまま動けなくて
With my eyes cast down, unable to move,
嫌われていないこと祈るばかり
I could only pray that I wasn't hated.
心全部見せてくれた
You showed me all of your heart,
何一つできなかったのに
even though I couldn't do a single thing.
どんな今を生きていますか
What kind of present are you living now?
好きだった歌はまだ聞こえますか
Can you still hear the songs you used to love?
くしゃみ一つで笑った泣き顔
A single sneeze turned a tearful face into laughter,
離れても側にいる気がしているよ
even if apart, I feel like you're by my side.
口先だけで繋ぎ止めて
Holding on with just lip service,
それでも離さない 一人は怖い
yet still not letting go, scared of being alone.
疲れ切った息を吐く
Exhaling a tired breath,
いろんなことが奇跡みたいに思えて
so many things feel like miracles,
どうしようもない
and there's nothing I can do.
少しずつ感じなくなっていく
Gradually starting to feel less,
悔しかった帰り道 忘れていく
forgetting the frustrating path back home.
そうしなきゃダメな時が来る
A time comes when you have to do so,
それでも否定否定できないことも判る
yet I understand there are things you can't deny.
黙ったままの指切り
A pinky promise made in silence,
何が分から分からないまま
without even knowing what I don't know.
星を呼んで位置を知るように
Like calling the stars to find our position,
君の声で僕は進めるんだ
your voice lets me move forward.
サヨナラを言った場所から離れても聞こえるよ
Even away from where we said goodbye, I can hear it,
約束が
the promise...
その胸にしまった日に憧れた
I longed for the day tucked away in that heart,
こんな思い気付かなかったでしょう
you probably didn't notice such feelings.
その日がその目に見えなくても
Even if that day is invisible to those eyes,
このまぶたの裏に柔らかく残る
it softly remains behind these eyelids.
サヨナラを言った場所には
At the place where goodbye was said,
君の声がずっと輝くんだ
your voice shines forever.
君が君を見失っても
Even if you lose sight of yourself,
僕が見つけ出せるよ
I will be able to find you.
君の声で
With your voice...
どんな今を生きていますか
What kind of present are you living now?
僕の歌が今聞こえますか
Can you hear my song right now?
くしゃみ一つで取り戻せるよ
With a single sneeze, we can take it back,
離れても側にいる 綺麗にいるよ
even if apart, I'm by your side, staying beautiful.
ということで、サザンクロスを歌わせていただきました！
And with that, I sang "Southern Cross"!
ちびニコたん、一緒に歌ってくれてありがとう！出ておいでー！
Chibi Nico-tan, thank you for singing with me! Come on out!
わーい！ありがとー！
Yay! Thank you!
ニコたんだー！
It's Nico-tan!
ニコたんだよー、ちびニコたん！
It's Nico-tan, Chibi Nico-tan!
ようやく会えたねー！
We finally met!
ってか本当にちっちゃいね！可愛い！
I mean, you're really tiny! So cute!
えへへ、ありがとー！
Ehehe, thank you!
うん、可愛い可愛い！
Yeah, so cute, so cute!
ってか、目の中に入れても痛くないんじゃない？自分だからねー！
I mean, wouldn't it not hurt to put you in my eye? Since you're me!
ってか、もう目の中に入れたいねー！食べちゃいたい！
Honestly, I want to put you in my eye! I wanna eat you up!
え、ちょっと何やって…
Eh, wait, what are you doing...
ん〜、可愛い！可愛い可愛い！
Mm~ so cute! So cute, so cute!
ちびニコたん、可愛くて…
Chibi Nico-tan, you're so cute...
さっきからニコちゃん怖いんだけど…
Nico-chan, you've been scary for a while now...
ごめんごめん！
Sorry, sorry!
ちびニコたん、この後大切なお知らせたくさんしなきゃいけないから、ちょっと待っててくれるかな？
Chibi Nico-tan, I have a lot of important announcements after this, so could you wait for a bit?
この後の面談でじっくりね！
We can talk thoroughly during our meeting after this!
あー、うん、分かった！
Ah, okay, I got it!
とりあえずニコちゃん、この後も頑張ってね！バイバーイ！
Anyway Nico-chan, do your best for the rest of it too! Bye-bye!
リスナーさんもバイバーイ！
Listeners, bye-bye too!
バイバイ、バイバイちびニコたん！あー、可愛いー！
Bye-bye, bye-bye Chibi Nico-tan! Ah, so cute!
はい！ということで、ちびニコちゃんに来ていただきました！
Alright! So, we had Chibi Nico-chan join us!
可愛かったねー！
That was so cute!
配信はまだまだ続くのですが、
The stream will keep going, but...
ここで告知行っとくか！
Let's get into the announcements now!
いくつかございます。
There are a few items.
まずは、こちら！
First up is this!
こがねニコ 誕生記念2026のグッズが出まーす！やったー！
Kogane Nicole Birthday Commemoration 2026 merch is coming out! Yay!
早速ね、1つずつグッズを紹介させてください。
Let me introduce the merch items one by one!
1つ目は、こちら。
First up is this one.
清楚ニコたん アクリルジオラマスタンド！
[Pure Nicole-tan Acrylic Diorama Stand]
イラストは本田ロアロ先生に描いていただきました。
The illustration was drawn by Roaro Honda-sensei.
今回の生誕のテーマをもとに、
Based on the theme for this birthday,
ディーヴァ清楚なニコたんをイメージして描いていただいてます！
it was drawn to image a pure diva Nicole-tan!
清楚なニコたんをね、ぜひアクリルジオラマスタンドとしてお家にお迎えしてください！
Please welcome pure Nicole-tan into your home as an acrylic diorama stand!
お次は、こちら！
Next up is this!
ちびニコたん ランダム缶バッジ！
[Chibi Nicole-tan Random Pin Badges]
今回もグッズ化してしまいました！
We turned her into merch again!
いろんな表情やポーズのちびニコたんが全部で4種類！
There are 4 types featuring Chibi Nicole-tan in various expressions and poses!
ランダムで1種類だけ入ってます。
Each contains 1 random badge.
どのちびニコたんが出てくるかは開けてからのお楽しみ！
Which Chibi Nicole-tan you get is a surprise until you open it!
続いては、こちら！
Next up is this!
ちびニコたんを0距離で？！ ぬいぐるみショルダーバッグ！
[Chibi Nicole-tan at Zero Distance?! Plush Shoulder Bag]
いつでもどこでもちびニコたんと一緒にお出かけできます。
You can go out together with Chibi Nicole-tan anytime, anywhere.
いろんなところに連れて行ってあげてください。
Please take her along everywhere!
あの、頭をあけてね、これ物入れられます。
You can open the head and put stuff inside.
最後は、こちら！
And lastly, this one!
獲物を見つけたニコたんぬいぐるみキーホルダー！
[Nicole-tan Who Found Her Prey Plush Keychain]
単体で持っていくもよし、
It's great on its own,
さっきのショルダーバッグにつけていくのもよし！
or attached to the shoulder bag from earlier!
いろんなところにつけてニコたん推しをアピールできますー！
Attach it anywhere to show off that you're a Nicole-tan fan!
改めてフルセットはこちら！
Here is the full set once again!
可愛いし、美しい！
It's cute and beautiful!
ちびニコたんを今回もね、グッズにできて、清楚なニコたんもグッズにできて本当に嬉しいです！
I'm so happy we could turn both Chibi Nicole-tan and Pure Nicole-tan into merch!
使いやすいものも多いのでね、ぜひゲットしてください！
Many items are very useful, so please get them!
さらにフルセット購入特典もございます。こちら！
Plus, there's a full set purchase bonus! Here!
フルセット購入特典！
[Full Set Purchase Bonus]
直筆サイン&箔押し複製メッセージ入りチケット風カード！ライブのチケットみたいになってます、今回の。
An autographed ticket-style card with a foil-stamped message! It looks like a concert ticket.
これと特典のASMRボイスが出ます！
This comes with a bonus ASMR voice track!
タイトルは「野生に戻ってしまった成人女性(虎)」です。
The title is 'Adult Female Who Reverted to the Wild (Tiger)'.
どういうことー？！
What does that mean?!
ちょっと！
Hold on!
最後に(虎)ってことはまあ、虎なんだよな。そういうことでいいよな？グッズさんよ。
Ending with '(Tiger)' means it's a tiger, right? Is that right, merch team?
ね、チケット風カードにはね、心を込めてすべてに手書きでサインをさせていただきます！
And on the ticket-style card, I'll put my heart into hand-signing every single one!
ボイスは虎として野生に戻ってしまったニコたんを取り戻しに来るリスナーというテーマで収録です。
The voice drama is recorded with the theme of a listener coming to retrieve Nicole-tan who reverted to a wild tiger.
どういうことなんだろう、本当に。
What is that even supposed to mean, seriously?
まあでもちょっと気になりますよね？ね、ぜひ聞いてみてください。
Well, but you're a bit curious, right? Please give it a listen!
ちなみに過去一恥ずかしそうな内容です。
By the way, it's my most embarrassing content yet.
グッズは配信後カートオープンです！
Merch sales open right after the stream!
フルセットは数量限定ではございません。なのでゆっくり購入してください。
The full set is not limited in quantity, so please take your time.
大事なお知らせはまだありますが...
There are still important announcements, but...
その前に1曲歌わせていただこうかなと思います。
before that, I'd like to sing a song for you.
ちょっとマイクも変えますね。
Let me switch mics real quick.
次の曲は、
The next song is...
ニコたんのことを知って応援してくれてる皆さんにとっても、とても思い出深いあの曲となっております。
a song full of special memories for everyone who supports me.
「歌ってみた」も出させていただいてる曲なんですけど、
It's a song I've also released a cover of,
みんな覚えてるかな？
I wonder if everyone remembers it?
それじゃあ聞いてください。「ヒカリヘ」。
Please listen to... "Hikari e".
理想 現実 ワンクリック 光の速度に変わっても
Ideal, reality, one click, even if changed to the speed of light
地球の裏より遠い距離 アダムとイヴにはなれない
A distance further than the other side of Earth, we can't be Adam and Eve
悲しみの生まれた場所たどって
Tracing back to where sadness was born
その傷やさしく触れて癒せたなら
If I could gently touch those wounds and heal them
溢れる想い 愛は君を照らす光になれる
My overflowing feelings, love can become the light that illuminates you
切ないほどに
So painfully deep...
たとえ描く未来 そこに私がいないとしても
Even if in the future we picture, I'm not there
いまはそっと抱きしめてあげる
Right now, I will gently hold you close
運命だって引き寄せて輝き続けたいよ
I want to draw fate near and keep on shining
奇跡だって起こせるって信じたい
I want to believe we can make miracles happen
信じた...
I believed...
遠慮 配慮 言葉の最後に
Hesitation, consideration at the end of words,
感情動かされても
Even if moved by emotion,
心の奥まで伝わらない
It doesn't reach deep into the heart.
(本当の声を聞かせて)
(Let me hear your true voice)
すべての事に終わりがあるのなら
If there is an end to everything,
苦しみさえ いつか消えるはずだから
Even suffering should disappear someday...
溢れる思い
Overflowing feelings,
愛は胸を焦がす
Love scorches my heart,
痛みに変わる いとおしいほどに
Turning into pain, so dearly.
たとえ世界中の声の聞こえに
Even if I were blamed by all the voices
責められたとしても
In the whole world,
あたしがずっと受け止めてあげる
I will always embrace and accept you.
人は悲しみを知るために生まれたの？
Were humans born to learn about sadness?
そんなことない もっと愛を知りたい
That's not true, I want to know love more.
孤独がぬくもりを知るためにあるのなら
If loneliness exists to learn warmth,
幸せはいつだってそこにあるのに
Even though happiness is always right there...
ああ
Ah...
溢れる思い
Overflowing feelings,
愛は君を照らすヒカリになれる
Love can become the light that illuminates you,
切ないほどに
So painful...
たとえ未来 そこにあたしがいないと知っても
Even if I know I won't be there in the future,
今はそっと抱きしめてあげる
Right now, I will gently hold you tight.
運命だって引き寄せて 輝き続けたいよ
I want to pull even fate close and keep shining.
奇跡だって起こせるって信じた
I believed that we could even work miracles...
信じた
I believed.
ということで、なんと！
And so, amazingly!
miwaさんにお越しいただきましたー！
We have miwa-san here as our guest!
miwaさーん！
miwa-san!
miwaさんだー！ 本物だー！
It's miwa-san! She's real!
触ってる！ すごい！
I'm touching her! Amazing!
miwaです！
I'm miwa!
miwaさん！
miwa-san!
Nicoさん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Nico-san, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！ めっちゃ嬉しいです！
Thank you so much! I'm so happy!
実はmiwaさんとは、デビュー当時の「歌ってみた」で『ヒカリへ』を歌わせていただきまして...
Actually, with miwa-san, I covered "Hikari e" back around my debut...
その時からのご縁で、まさかこうして一緒に歌えるなんて本当に夢のようでございます！
And thanks to that connection, to actually sing together like this is truly like a dream!
こちらこそです！ とっても嬉しいです！
Likewise! I'm so happy!
そして、ここでなんと！ 重大発表2つ目がございます！
And now, amazingly, we have our second major announcement!
なんと！ miwaさんに作詞作曲をしていただいた、Nicoたん初めてのオリ曲が決まりましたー！
Amazingly, Nico's very first original song, written and composed by miwa-san, has been decided!
miwaさん、そのタイトルをぜひ発表していただいてもいいでしょうか？
miwa-san, could you please announce the title for us?
私でいいんでしょうか？
Is it really okay for me to do it?
当たり前じゃないですか！
Of course it is!
それでは発表させていただきます。
Then, I will announce it.
タイトルは...『誓焔』です！
The title is... "Seien"!
星の炎と書いて『誓焔』です。
Written with the characters for "star" and "flame", it's "Seien".
実は今回のライブのタイトルにもなっています。『誓焔 -Fire Astra Diva-』。
Actually, it's also the title of this live concert: "Seien -Fire Astra Diva-".
今回のセットリストも星と炎の曲で作られていて...
Today's setlist was also built around songs of stars and flames...
最後にこれからmiwaさんに作っていただいた『誓焔』を歌わせていただきます！
And finally today, I will perform "Seien", written for me by miwa-san!
Nicoたんがホロライブに来て、miwaさんと出会ったり、嬉しいこともたくさんありながら...
Nico coming to Hololive, meeting miwa-san, having so many happy moments...
やっぱり活動で悩んだことだったり、辛いこととか...
But also struggling with worries about my activities, painful things...
届けたい想いとか、そういうものががいっぱいあったんですけど
I had so many thoughts and feelings I wanted to deliver...
それを全部miwaさんに聞いてもらって...
I had miwa-san listen to all of it...
あの、歌詞をね、作っていただきました。曲も作っていただきました。
and she wrote the lyrics for me. She composed the music too.
本当にmiwaさん、ありがとうございます！
miwa-san, thank you so much!
ありがとうございます！もう本当に光栄です。
Thank you so much! It's truly an honor.
ね、ニコさんの曲一緒に書けて本当に光栄ですし、今日一緒に「ヒカリへ」歌えて本当に嬉しかったです。
It was such an honor to write a song for you, Nicon, and I was so happy to sing "Hikari e" together today.
本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
では、この後歌う新曲「星炎」、楽しみにしてるね！
I'm really looking forward to your new song "Seien" that you're singing next!
私もみんなと一緒にそこで見てるよ！
I'll be watching over there with everyone!
あ、そこに居るの！？
Wait, you're gonna be right there?!
皆さんこれからもよろしくお願いします！
Everyone, please continue to support us!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you for your support!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
バイバーイ！頑張って！
Bye-bye! Good luck!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
よし！あーもうmiwaさん、可愛いし美しいし...声は素晴らしいしもう素敵だし本当に本物のmiwaさんだ...
Alright! Ah, miwa-san is so cute, beautiful... Her voice is wonderful, she's so lovely... She really is the real miwa-san...
ということで、新曲を歌うためにステージに移動したいと思います。
So now, I'd like to move to the main stage to perform my new song.
聞いてください。「星炎」。
Please listen: "Seien".
星炎
[Song: Seien]
自信なんてなかった
I had no confidence at all,
ひとりだってよかった
I was fine being all alone.
プライドに隠れて
Hiding behind my pride,
誰かの視線 気になってばかりで
always worrying about how others saw me,
閉じこもってた
I kept myself locked away.
綺麗だなんて 思えなくて
I couldn't think of myself as beautiful,
笑えなかったんだ
and I couldn't even smile.
涙で滲んだ 画面の向こう
Beyond the screen, blurred through my tears,
ふいに溶けた心
my heart suddenly melted
触れてくれた声
at the voice that touched me.
「君のおかげで笑えたよ」
"Thanks to you, I was able to smile."
その言葉がずっと
Those words have always
この胸を灯す
lit up my heart,
ただ一つの光
as my one and only light.
Fire, take me higher
消えそうな声を 歌に変えて
Turning my fading voice into a song,
弱さ 抱きしめながら
while embracing my weaknesses,
届けと叫ぶように 燃やす炎
I burn a flame, as if shouting to reach you.
Fire, take me higher
君の明日を照らしたい
I want to illuminate your tomorrow.
救われたくて 100以上出し切って
Wanting to be saved, giving more than 100%,
疲れ果てた夜
on nights when I was exhausted,
大事なものって 何だったっけ
I almost forgot
忘れそうになるの
what was truly important.
振り返る足跡
Looking back at my footsteps,
あの頃の自分に会いたい
I want to meet the person I was back then.
もう戻れなくても
Even if I can never go back,
素直になりたい
I want to be honest with myself,
失くしたくないから
because I don't want to lose it.
Fire, take me higher
君への想い 歌に乗せて
Carrying my feelings for you in this song,
こわさ 受け止めながら
while facing my fears,
響けと祈るように 燃やす炎
I burn a flame, as if praying for it to resound.
Fire, take me higher
君の笑顔を灯したい
I want to light up your smile.
壊れそうな夜をこえて
Overcoming nights that felt like I'd break,
逃げ出しそうな朝をぬけて
passing through mornings I wanted to run from,
いま ここにいる
I am standing here now.
私のつくる世界で 君が笑ってくれるなら
If you can smile in the world I create,
この声が生まれた理由
that's the reason this voice was born,
胸にともる星炎
the star's flame burning in my heart.
Fire, take me higher
私に意味をくれた君へ
To you, who gave me meaning,
声は届いてますか
can you hear my voice?
これからもずっと歩き続けたい
I want to keep walking forward forever
Fire, take me higher
消えそうな声を歌に変えて
Turning my fading voice into song
弱さを抱きしめながら
While embracing my weakness
届けと
Wishing for it to reach you...
叫ぶように燃やす炎
I burn like a flame, as if shouting out
Fire, take me higher
君の明日を照らしたい
I want to illuminate your tomorrow
ニコたんの歌を聴いてくれてありがとう
Thank you for listening to Nicotan's song.
ご来場ありがとうございました！！
[Thank you for coming!!]